Guide to the Don Hobart Collection 1960-1971
Oregon Historical Society, Research Library
- Series B: Wild World of People, 1960-1971
  - WWP08 Mt. St. Helens Climb - Snake River Treasure Hunt: Mt. St. Helen's Story (mountain climbing skier), Snake River Treasure Hunt (modern treasure hunt in old mines and battlefields). Snake River Treasure Hunt: The Snake River runs straight north between the borders of Idaho (on the east) and Oregon (on the west). North of Ontario, Oregon, the river plunges into a canyon over 5,000 feet deep and over 100 miles long. Roads are few and very rough. The way to travel the easy way is by 47 foot mail boat from Lewiston, Idaho, which goes up the river 92 miles. The canyon is filled with wildlife, beautiful scenery, towering cliffs and a lot of history. Old mine shafts, lost cabins and Indian battlegrounds. A modern day treasure hunter's paradise. SS: MT. HELEN'S STORY - Mt. Saint Helen provides ideal mountain climbing adventures and offers an expert skier a chance to match his skills against the face of a glacier, jump huge crevices with expert form and grace. SNAKE RIVER TREASURE HUNT - beautiful scenery and treacherous waters in a canyon 5,000 feet deep provide the setting for a modern treasure hunt through old mines and battlefields. TURKEY RACE - feathers fly and turkeys fly as their owners prod them into racing. BATH TUB RACE - a bathtub race with no winner. MOTOCROSS motorcycle enthusiasts try anything in the motocross. NOTE: SEGMENTS ALSO USED IN EPISODE 21 (07408)
  - WWP09 Mattawa Motorcycle - Mexico: Mexicao the Easy Way (underwater film of divers in Gulf of California), Desert Bike Race (sand dune in Washington) SS: MEXICO THE EASY WAY - living off the waters of the Gulf of California features exciting underwater film of divers playing with giant turtles in crystal clear water. DESERT BIKE RACE - a real test of skill and endurance as hundreds of motorcycles race in the sand dunes of Washington with hilarious slow motion spills and revealing close-ups of the faces of the men who brave the desert on motorcycles. WATER SKIING - a water skiing ballet with th water, sun and speed directing the music. SAILING THE CATAMARANS - the tiny catamaran shows its keel to most sailboats with speeds up to 25 mph. NOTE: SEGMENTS ALSO USED IN EPISODE 25 (07409)
  - WWP10 Tide Out Table Set - Alaska, Winter Playground: Mexico the Easy Way (divers and giant turtles), Desert Bike Race (motorcycle race in sand dunes in Washington). Tide Out Table Set: A houseboat trip up into the fiords of British Columbia bring the camera crews into a seafood Garden of Eden. The rugged coastline offers hundreds of miles of waterways abounding with oyster beds, scallops, and clams for the digging. Underwater cameras follow the divers through the clear cold waters. SS: TIDE OUT-TABLE SET - a beautiful scenic houseboat cruise through the fiords of British Columbia as seafood lovers invade the beaches and the deep six in search of a feast of plenty. ALASKA: WINTER PLAYGROUND - a winter celebration in honor of Alaska's fur trapping ancestors featuring spills and pile-ups in ski contents, snowmobile and sled dog races. DESCHUTES RIVER ADVENTURE - a fishing trip on the beautiful Deschutes River in Oregon. NEVADA CAMEL RACES - a completely ridiculous fiasco in the famed Virginia City, Nevada. NOTE: SEGMENTS ALSO USED IN EPISODE 16 (07410)
  - WWP11 Hellbay Florida - Jolly Copters - Snowmobile Trout: Hell's Bay (Florida Everglades back country), Jolly Copters (build own helicopter), Winter Trout (Madison River, Wyoming) SS: HELL'S BAY - they call it Hell's Bay in the Florida Everglades because once you enter the swamps, survival takes precedence over all else, featuring fishing and exploring the back country. JOLLY 'COPTERS - a man with a unique hobby--he builds his own helicopters and the hopes they will get airborne and stay there. WINTER TROUT - Wyoming fishermen can't wait for the spring thaw. In mid-February they take their snowmobiles up the Madison River to do some trout fishing with temperatures dropping to 20 degrees below zero. COME FLY WITH ME - a school for would-be acrobatic skiers. Double flips and wild crashes while wearing a pair of skis. NOTE: SEGMENTS ALSO USED IN EPISODE 15 (07411)
  - WWP12 Two Top Ice People - Sand Castles - Divers Fun Day: Two Top's Ice People (snowmobiling in Two Top Mountain on Continental Divide in Montana), Sand Castles (sand sculpturing day on Oregon coast) SS: TWO TOP'S ICE PEOPLE - a snowmobile escapade to the summit of Two Top Mountain 9,00 feet above sea level on the Continental Divide in Montana. In the dead of winter, trees shrouded in ice take on the appearance of towering ghostly ice people. SAND CASTLES - thousands of people of all ages invade the Oregon beaches to create sand sculptures of unbelievable proportions only to watch the afternoon tide erase all traces of their work. LOW & SLOW - move over birds, the hang gliders are here! A young sport that really began in 1860. Gliding from a hill overlooking San Francisco Bay on a homemade glider which can be built for as little as $9.30 and flies like crazy. A new sport sweeping the nation. NOTE: SEGMENTS ALSO USED IN EPISODE 14 (07412)
  - WWP13 Wild World of People - Wrap Up #1: Kaleidoscope in Action (remake of WWP promotional film, mixing past show excerpts and future show excerpts) SS: TILLAMOOK ENDURO - 100 miles of rough mountain trails on a motorcycle. WHEEL TO WHEEL - four wheel drive vehicles compete on a drag strip and around a fast and rough wheel to wheel course. PLAISTED POLAR EXPEDITION - a try at the North Pole across the Arctic Ocean on snowmobiles. KALEIDOSCOPE OF ACTION - a remake of the promotion film provides an exciting overview of the Wild World of People. Scenes from past show in 16 fast-paced segments featuring people from coast to coast and the crazy thing they do to have fun. NOTE: SEGMENTS ALSO USED IN EPISODE 26 (07413)
  - WWP14 Low & Slow "Hang Gliders": Low & Slow (hang gliders in San Francisco Bay). Low and Slow: On a windy hill overlooking San Francisco Bay, the Wild World of People crews cover a budding new sport called hang gliding. A sport that is sure to sweep the country because it is an inexpensive way to get off the ground. Since the beginning of time man has stood on the brow if a hill and dreamed of spreading his arms and flying away like a hawk, with no controls, no complicated instruments to worry about. To soar and wheel through the sky with no motor noise, the sound of the wind as your air speed indicator and your sense of fear as your altimeter. The hang glider pilot and his frail craft are coming pretty close to that dream. SS: LOW & SLOW - move over birds, the hang gliders are here! A young sport that really began in 1860. Gliding from a hill overlooking San Francisco Bay on a homemade glider which can be built for as little as $9.30 and flies like crazy. A new sport sweeping the nation. NOTE: CROSSOVER WITH SAME TITLED SEGMENT IN EPISODE 12 [No film for WWP15 Available] [no print] (07414)
  - WWP16 Deschutes Drift - Nevada Camel Race: Deschutes River Adventure (steelhead fishing, 60 mile white water drift along Deschutes River Canyon), Camel Race (camel and ostrich races in Virginia City, NV). Virginia City Camel Races: Once a year, which is often enough, in Virginia City, Nevada, they hold a camel race. Years ago when the silver mines of Virginia City were going full tilt, someone had a great idea. Why not bring camels to Nevada to transport food and equipment across the desert? The camel races are to commemorate this momentous occasion and the only way to describe the results is...out of control. The ships of the desert don't take kindly to being saddled and ridden by an amateur camel rider, so anything can happen and generally does. SS: DESCHUTES RIVER ADVENTURE - a fishing trip on the beautiful Deschutes River in Oregon. NEVADA CAMEL RACES - a completely ridiculous fiasco in the famed Virginia City, Nevada. NOTE: CROSSOVER WITH SAME TITLED SEGMENT IN EPISODE 10 (07415)
  - WWP17 Survival School: Survival School (finding food and shelter in the mountains) SS: SURVIVAL SCHOOL - living off the land, for real. A week in the mountains with a survival class; how and where to find food and how to prepare it. The class is taught by one of the top experts in the survival field. NOTE: CROSSOVER WITH SAME TITLED SEGMENT IN EPISODE 2 (07416)
  - WWP18 Motorcycle Hill Climb - Inner Tubes & Snow: Hills & Spills (motorcyclist climb up and innertube riders go down steep hills)Motorcycle Hill Climb - Inner Tubes & Snow: Hills & Spills (motorcyclist climb up and innertube riders go down steep hills) SS: HILLS & SPILLS - some want to go up and other want to go down! The motorcyclists do their level best to climb a steep hill and innertube riders almost kill themselves going down. Slow motion spills galore. NOTE: CROSSOVER WITH SAME TITLED SEGMENT IN EPISODE 5 [no print] (07417)
  - WWP19 Black Powder Shooters - Chain Saw Artistry: Muzzle-Loaders (black powder rifle shooting), Chain Saw Artistry (chain saw sculpture) SS: MUZZLE LOADERS - "mountain men" in buckskins and moccasins show off their shooting skills. CHAIN-SAW ARTISTRY - watch a wooden indian evolve from a cedar log. NOTE: CROSSOVER WITH SAME TITLED SEGMENT IN EPISODE 3 (07418)
  - WWP20 Jr. Rodeo - Motorcycle Mountain Enduro: Junior Rodeo (calf roping in White Swan, Washington) SS: JUNIOR RODEO - in White Swan, Washington, the youngster set takes to the arena in their own rodeo that is almost as rough as the "grown-up" kind. NOTE: CROSSOVER WITH SAME TITLED SEGMENT IN EPISODE 4 (07419)
  - WWP21 Parachute Fun Day - Turkey Race - Estacada Bathtub Race: Turkey Race (turkey race), Bath Tub Race (floating bath tub race), Moto-Cross (moto-cross with slow motion) SS: TURKEY RACE - feathers fly and turkeys fly as their owners prod them into racing. BATH TUB RACE - a bathtub race with no winner. MOTOCROSS motorcycle enthusiasts try anything in the motocross. NOTE: CROSSOVER WITH SAME TITLED SEGMENT IN EPISODE 8 (07420)
  - WWP22 Gold & Grisslys [Grizzlies] - Treasure Hunt (Metal Detector): Treasure Hunt (hunt coins with metal detectors), Gold and Grizzlys (pan gold in Alaska) SS: SS: TREASURE HUNT - how to look for gold and treasure with a metal detector. GOLD AND GRIZZLYS - a trip to Alaska to pan gold with a real old timer who doesn't need a metal detector to find gold. NOTE: CROSSOVER WITH SAME TITLED SEGMENT IN EPISODE 6 (07421)
  - WWP23 Ye Olde Jousting Society: jousting tournament with armor and lances SS: YE OLD JOUSTING SOCIETY - mad dogs and Englishmen, and all that! A real medieval jousting tournament with full armor and real lances. Color, beautiful horses, pageantry and sore muscles. NOTE: CROSSOVER WITH SAME TITLED SEGMENT IN EPISODE 1 (07422)
  - WWP24 Winnamucca Dog Trails - A Dog Named Cat: Winnemucca Dog Trails (Chukar trail in Winnemucca, Nevada), Dog Named Cat ("Cat" kills rattlesnakes) SS: WINNEMUCCA DOG TRIALS - the top field-trial dogs of the nation show up at this tough Nevada Chukar trials. A DOG NAMED CAT - a dog named "Cat" kills rattlesnakes for fun; a weird dance of death in slow motion. NOTE: CROSSOVER WITH SAME TITLED SEGMENT IN EPISODE 7 (07423)
  - WWP25 Water Skiing - Aqua Cat Sailing: Water Skiing (water skiing ballet), Sailing the Catamarans (Catamaran sailing up to 25 mph) SS: WATER SKIING - a water skiing ballet with the water, sun and speed directing the music. SAILING THE CATAMARANS - the tiny catamaran shows its keel to most sailboats with speeds up to 25 mph. NOTE: CROSSOVER WITH SAME TITLED SEGMENT IN EPISODE 9 (07424)
  - WWP26 Wild World of People - Wrap Up #2: Tillamook Enduro (100 mile motorcycle race), Four Wheel Games (jeeps on 4WD rig game course track), Plaisted Polar Expedition (snowmobiles cross Artic Ocean - 1st overland attempt to reach North Pole) SS: TILLAMOOK ENDURO - 100 miles of rough mountain trails on a motorcycle. WHEEL TO WHEEL - four wheel drive vehicles compete on a drag strip and around a fast and rough wheel to wheel course. PLAISTED POLAR EXPEDITION - a try at the North Pole across the Arctic Ocean on snowmobiles. NOTE: CROSSOVER WITH SAME TITLED SEGMENT IN EPISODE 13 (07425)
  - WWPp Promo using segments from past episodes of Wild World of People (07426)
- Series C: Don Hobart Others & Unknowns
  - DHO01 "extra canada - original - big horn - elk - road shots" (07427)
  - DHO02 "Hood River Story" (07428)
  - DHO03 Hoodland Fire Department labeled on fire truck. Test for managing fires. Explosion titles: 1. Norox HF 5.5% AO 2 EHA Diluent 2. Norox MEXP-9 9% AO 3. Norox FS - 100/9 9% 4. MEKP 5.5% AO Ethyl Acetate Diluent (07429)
  - DHO04 Frontier reenactment gun shooting competition. Men and women competing. Closeups of loading rifles with powder, ball bullets, maintaining rifle, rifle parts, shots on paper and object targets, hatchet throwing. Closes with closeup of CAL 45. (07430)
  - DHO05 2 segments. 1st is a montage of Wild World of People (in credit) excerpts - includes white water rafting, speedboat race, jet boat, "Idaho Queen 3", skiing into thawing water, fish catching, snowmobiling, ski jumps, underwater shots of turtle, fish, 4 wheeler mud race, water rafting, kayaks, rams, plane take off. Segment 2 follows 2 men and later a 3rd for a hunting party in Alaska with shots of sheep, climbing, camping, Alaskan belt buckle, flying in/out, pontoon plane, moose, taking moose antlers from kills - DHU15 shares shots from 2nd segment (07431)
  - DHO06 "Trout Unlimited" - underwater and above shots of trout (07432)
  - DHO07 "The Way to the Top" - timberline lodge, summer. Qualifier ski races either to work at lodge or for a team. Quick shots of resort, swimming, and eating meals at lodge (07433)
  - DHS01 “The River – narration sound” (07434)
  - DHS02 mag track - no markings (07435)
  - DHS03 mag track - no markings (07436)
  - DHU01 sheep shearing, wool packed and shipped on boat on snake river likely between Idaho and Washington, boat "Idaho Queen II" (07437)
  - DHU02 Construction demolition explosion of industrial chimney including setup of wiring. Possibly part of dilapidated building shot, likely St. Vincent hospital. (07438)
  - DHU03 title credit "Prudence en Motoneige" ("caution in snowmobiling") snowmobile safety video, brand: Bradbun product: Ski-doo, illustrations of early snowmobiles, safety checks, jumps, getting stuck, riding gear, mechanical details, end credit "Bombardier Limitee, Montral, Quebec" public service with the Canadian Council of Security, Don Hobart Producer. (07439)
  - DHU04 wedding home video, credit "The Marriage of a Mariner - OR - Pollard Walks the Plank" "starring James Polland & Mary Jane Andrews" (couple getting married) music score: Pat Burke, dress design Dot Hobart (Don Hobart's wife), Holy Cross Church, people coming to ceremony, ceremony, procession out, reception at house, "just married" car drive away. (07440)
  - DHU05 making crab trap, sizing crabs, making fishing hooks, fishing and catches of catfish, underwater shots of fish, river fishing, end credit: Hobart Film Productions (07441)
  - DHU06 fishing motorboat on Bonneville Sturgeon and Walley, close up of catches, possible repeat takes, on/off shots of each catch. (07442)
  - DHU07 plane landing, fly in/out of range, plane boarding, sign "Unalakleet Alaska, Fishing Capital of the Artic", tractor making dam in water, Alaskan Eskimo/white family, children and adults with moose head and antlers, garden, white husband and eskimo wife share the local jewelry and art he has made. (07443)
  - DHU08 Manmade fire explosion to burn off natural fire brush, worker hiking with ropes attached with cans for small explosion over acres of mountainside, shots of rope/can exploding to create localized fires, after shots once fire has burned off. (07444)
  - DHU09 Showcases safety of using tire chains and how to use, trucks in snow swerving without tires chains and smooth turning with tire chains, Oregon main route in snowy mountains, possibly mount hood or coastal routes since views of waves, truck sign "Quick Grip Tire Chains." (07445)
  - DHU10 Outer marking on tape: "Ringneck - Canada Wildlife", closeup of autumn trees and leaves in water, rams, elk, reindeer, small plane arrives and departs, pheasant hunt with family and kids. (07446)
  - DHU11 Gifford Pinchot National Forest: Spirit Lake (sign), closeup bug, forest, waterfall, Bluff Lake Trail (sign), driving on dirt road, Shorthon Trail (sign), Bird Creek (sign), Longview Ski Club Ski Shelter (sign), register to climb signs, log-stacking trucks, boating in lake, Packwood Lake Trail (sign), cabin, summer views of mountain. (07447)
  - DHU12 Sign "This is Galice" (town), kayak, raft, rowboat, canoe multi-day excursion by approximately dozen men down Rogue River in southern Oregon between Roseburg and Eugene. Shots of boats, from boats, communal cooking, swimming, jumping out, packing up boats at end. (07448)
  - DHU13 “Eskimo Inn” sign, single and 2 engine planes, pontoon, horseback camping hiking excursion approx. 7 people upward into mountain, building tent in snow, rabbit trap and caught, shots from inside plane, skinning off moose antlers and moose meat, packing up plane to leave. (07449)
  - DHU14 Alaska views from small plane, hunting ram, elk or reindeer, bear, moose - hunters keep moose antlers, hiking with antlers - antlers shots same as DHU10. (07450)
  - DHU15 Going through border into Canada, pass Dawson Creek (sign) into Yukin Territory (sign), map graphic inlaid, spring camping, glacier closeup, fox, bald eagle, rams, vultures, bear, washing clothes in hot pot and stream, patching up plane wing with banged coffee tin and tape. (07451)